Class of 1879 Records, 1844-1984
Smith College Archives
Class of 1879 Records
1844-1984
Smith College. Class of 1879.
RG 80 UUID:b197b45b-2253-4939-ba27-c34c3db91915
6 boxes (60 linear inches)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection contains black and white photographs, programs, magazine and newspaper articles, lists of students, letters, correspondence, and information about the commencement and reunions of Smith College's first graduating class.
The Class of 1879 was the first graduating class of Smith College.
The Class of 1879 Records contain materials describing the history of the students of the first graduating class of Smith College. Types of materials include black and white photographs, programs, magazine and newspaper articles, lists of students, letters, correspondence, and information about the Class of 1879's commencement and reunions.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1879 Records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- Class of 1879: Commencement 1879 (Box 1380, Folder 1)
- Class of 1879: Baccalaureate 1879 (Box 1380, Folder 2)
- Class of 1879: Chronology 1875-1879 (Box 1380, Folder 3)
- Class of 1879: Clippings 1879 (Box 1380, Folder 4)
- Class of 1879: Commencement Music 1879 (Box 1380, Folder 5)
- Class of 1879: Concert and Reception 1878 (Box 1380, Folder 6)
- Class of 1879: Group Photos 1879 (Box 1380, Folder 7)
- Class of 1879: History 1876-77, 1879, 1932, 1934, 1938 (Box 1380, Folder 8)
- Class of 1879: Reunions (1925) 1925 (Box 1380, Folder 9)
- Class of 1879: Reunions (1929) 1929 (Box 1380, Folder 10)
- Class of 1879: Reunions (Photographs) 1929 (Box 1380, Folder 11)
- Class of 1879: Senior Reception (Box 1380, Folder 12)
- Class of 1879: Sophomore Reception to 1880 1877 (Box 1380, Folder 13)
- Class of 1879: Subjects for Essays 1879 (Box 1380, Folder 14)
- Class of 1879: Adkins, Mary (Correspondence) 1930, 1937-39, 1940-41, 1965 (Box 1380, Folder 15)
- Class of 1879: Adkins, Mary (Photographs) 1879, 1934 (Box 1380, Folder 16)
- Class of 1879: Bonney, Mary Herrick (Photographs) 1879 (Box 1380, Folder 17)
- Class of 1879: Carleton, Abbie Harriet (Correspondence) 1929 (Box 1380, Folder 18)
- Class of 1879: Cushing, Eleanor Philbrook (Box 1380, Folder 19)
- Class of 1879: Edwards, Adelaide Frances Dyer (Photographs) 1879 (Box 1380, Folder 20)
- Class of 1879: Gorham, Mary Etta (Box 1380, Folder 21)
- Class of 1879: Gulliver, Julia Henrietta 1879, 1910, 1912-14, 1915, 1917 (Box 1380, Folder 22)
- Class of 1879: Leonard, Henrietta 1897, 1938 (Box 1380, Folder 23)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Box 1380, Folder 24)
- Class of 1879: Osborne, Alice Cook 1879, 1929 (Box 1380, Folder 25)
- Class of 1879: Palmer, Anna Louise 1879 (Box 1380, Folder 26)
- Class of 1879: Spaulding, Sylvia Sanders 1918-1920 (Box 1380, Folder 27)
- Class of 1879: Taber, Sarah (Box 1380, Folder 28)
- Class of 1879: Tuckerman, Corinne Marie 1875, 1929, 1931, 1938-39 (Box 1380, Folder 29)
- Class of 1879: Warner, Harriet Blanche 1870-71, 1875, 1880, 1925, 1929, 1930-32 (Box 1381, Folder 1)
- Class of 1879: Warner, Harriet Blanche (Correspondence with Charles S. Palmer) 1930, 1932-41 (Box 1381, Folder 2)
- Class of 1879: Warner, Harriet Blanche (First Days at Smith College) 1923 (Box 1381, Folder 3)
- Class of 1879: Warner, Harriet Blanche (Lithography / Photographs) 1923, 1926 (Box 1381, Folder 4)
- Class of 1879: Warner, Harriet Blanche (Lecture Notes / Physics) 1878 (Box 1381, Folder 5)
- Class of 1879: Warner, Harriet Blanche (Lecture Notes) 1876-78 (Box 1381, Folder 6)
- Class of 1879: Warner, Harriet Blanche (Course Notes) undated (Box 1381, Folder 7)
- Class of 1879: Whiton, Mary Bartlett (Correspondence) 1883, 1906, 1924, 1929, 1930-31, 1933-39 (Box 1381, Folder 8)
- Class of 1879: Whiton, Mary Bartlett (Photographs) 1879, 1888-89, 1896, 1934, 1937 (Box 1381, Folder 9)
- Class of 1879: Whiton, Mary Bartlett (Scrapbook) Late 1800s-Early 1900s (Box 1381, Folder 10)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (General) 1875-86, 1900, 1904, 1909-10, 1913 (Box 1382, Folder 1)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Manuscripts, Typescripts, etc.) undated (Box 1382, Folder 2)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Ph.D. Degree) 1881-82, 1917, 1956, 1961, 1983-84 (Box 1382, Folder 3)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Photo Album) undated (Box 1382, Folder 4)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Morris Family History) undated (Box 1382, Folder 5)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Photographs) 1875-76, 1896, 1968-69 (Box 1382, Folder 6)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Publications) 1884, 1896, 1898-99, 1901-06, 1915, 1924 (Box 1382, Folder 7)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Twigs From a Family Tree) 1936 (Box 1382, Folder 8)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (A Valley Family by Alice Cone Perry) undated (Box 1382, Folder 9)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Correspondence with Ellen W. Clarke) 1875-1879 (Box 1383, Folder 1)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Correspondence with Ellen W. Clarke) 1876-1884 (Box 1383, Folder 2)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Correspondence with Charles Cone) 1882-83, 1895, 1897 (Box 1383, Folder 3)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Correspondence with Family) 1844, 1867, 1896, 1901, 1905, 1911 (Box 1383, Folder 4)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Correspondence- General) 1879, 1880-82, 1929 (Box 1383, Folder 5)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Correspondence- General) 1883, 1902-03, 1909, 1913, 1924-25, 1927-29 (Box 1383, Folder 6)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Correspondence with Almira N. Morris) 1871-1879 (Box 1383, Folder 7)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Correspondence with Almira N. Morris) 1880-1893 (Box 1383, Folder 8)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Correspondence with Alice Perry (Cone)) 1897, 1904-06, 1929, 1938-41, 1958 (Box 1383, Folder 9)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Correspondence with L. Clark Seelye) 1903, 1914, 1916, 1920, 1922 (Box 1383, Folder 10)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Journal) 1883-1887 (Box 1384, Folder 1)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Journal) 1887 (Box 1384, Folder 2)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Journal) 1893-1895 (Box 1384, Folder 3)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Journal) 1896-1899 (Box 1384, Folder 4)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Journal) 1900-1908 (Box 1384, Folder 5)
- Class of 1879: Morris, Kate E. (Journal) 1909-1929 (Box 1384, Folder 6)
- Harriet Blanche Warner (Photograph Album) undated (Box 1384.1)